Do you know this logo? Probably not, but
it's a company that's about to make
Trump and his family billions.
Trump doubled his fortune within a year
thanks to crypto. The Trump family is
positioning themselves as major players
in the industry, leveraging the
presidency like no one before them. So,
investigative reporters took a closer
look at their crypto ventures, and they
uncovered a story of get-richqu advisers
and dating gurus turned business
partners, a foreign investment, White
House access for sale, posted fraud
lawsuits, and presidential pardons. The
world's most powerful man is reshaping
an industry his businesses are deeply
invested in. And somehow outside that
industry, hardly anyone seems to notice.
How did the Trump family pull this off?
That's why I am rich
though I got no money. No,
I am rich.
Isn't it funny
though?
This video is partially based on an
investigative report by Eric Lipton,
David Yaffy Balani and Ben Protest for
the New York Times. You'll find the link
in the description.
In 2019, Trump tweeted, quote, "I'm not
a fan of Bitcoin and other
cryptocurrencies which are not money and
whose value is highly volatile and based
on thin air. unregulated crypto assets
can facilitate unlawful behavior,
including drug trade and other illegal
activity. In 2021, he said,
>> "Bitcoin, I I just seems like a scam."
>> But by July 2024, he said this during a
Bitcoin conference in Nashville.
>> This afternoon, I'm laying out my plan
to ensure that the United States will be
the crypto capital of the planet and the
Bitcoin superpower of the world.
A stark turnaround.
What happened?
When Biden enters office in 2020, his
administration increases regulation of
the crypto industry in several ways. The
goal is to better protect investors from
the risks and volatility of the crypto
market. Most importantly, the Biden
administration empowers the Securities
and Exchange Commission to regulate
crypto companies. The SEC goes into
action under the newly appointed
chairman Gary Gensler. It starts
charging crypto companies to create
legal precedent. For example, the agency
goes after the creators of the Terara
cryptocurrency. Terra wiped out $40
billion in market value when it
collapsed in 2022. It charges the
responsible company and its founder with
orchestrating a multi-billion dollar
crypto asset securities fraud.
The SEC argues that cryptocurrencies are
simply securities, a financial asset
like stocks. That definition comes with
a whole set of compliance requirements
which crypto companies often don't meet.
So, the agency goes after them for
listing unregistered securities, for
misleading marketing, and for failing to
register tokens as securities.
Within 3 and 1/2 years, the agency
issues roughly $6 billion in total
penalties across about 100 cases.
The crypto industry doesn't like it. In
their view, it doesn't make sense to
treat all crypto as securities.
According to them, they don't fit the
definition. They want less regulation.
And so do many crypto enthusiasts who
feel that the Biden administration is
hostile towards crypto. Enter the
presidential race of 2024. A sizable
chunk of voters is worried about this
issue. Over 50 million Americans own
crypto and over 2 million join a crypto
advocacy group. Politically, it makes
sense for Trump to change course to
appeal to these voters and corporations
frustrated with his opponent.
>> I pledge to the Bitcoin community that
the day I take the oath of office, Joe
Biden and Camala Harris's anti-crypto
crusade will be over. it will end on day
one. I will fire Gary Gensler and
appoint a new SEC chairman.
He first dipped his toes into crypto in
2022 with an NFT collection. He claims
seeing how many people paid in crypto
for these NFTs changed his mind on the
issue. Also, he begins to receive
sizable donations from crypto companies
for his presidential campaign. This
election is the first time the crypto
industry went allin on lobbying efforts,
but another thing is happening behind
the scenes.
Donald Junior and Eric are the key
players in the Trump family's business
operations. According to the New York
Times, they supposedly convinced their
dad that embracing crypto would not just
be a smart political move, they could
also make quite a bit of money with it.
They came up with two ideas, a coin and
a bank. Both will be incredibly
successful.
It's not just money. Our lives are
increasingly digital. But until
recently, mobile internet was annoyingly
physical. We travel a lot for our
reporting and a hefty roaming charge
will scare flight mode right into you.
But recently, we completely switched to
Sy's ESIM service. No more hustle to
find a SIM on site. No more ripoffs and
insane roaming charges. SY gets us
instant Eim data in 200 destinations.
That's fast, borderless connectivity
straight from our phones. Just download
the app, pick one of their many, many
plans, and install with a few clicks.
Their pricing is more than fair, and you
can easily top up. It's legitimately a
gamecher. And that's not all. SY comes
with a bunch of useful extras. A virtual
location feature for more privacy and an
ad blocker that saves up to 28.6% data.
And right now you can get an exclusive
15% discount on sale data plans. Simply
download the app and use code Fern TV at
checkout. We can wholeheartedly
recommend it.
Meme coins are like digital
collectibles. There's a limited supply
for each coin and if one takes off, its
value can skyrocket. On January 17,
Trump unveils his own memecoin. It comes
with a disclaimer that it's not an
investment opportunity and has nothing
to do with any political office. The
launch goes extremely well. Millions of
people buy it. Within days, it becomes
one of the most popular and valuable
meme coins in the world. Two Trump
businesses control 80% of all coins, a
share worth 58 billion at one point.
That would be about 90% of Trump's net
worth. Shortly after, the value
plummeted and so far never recovered. In
consequence, nearly half of the people
who bought this coin lost money. A tiny
group of people made enormous profits.
The Trump family hasn't actually sold
their coins, which are still
theoretically worth billions, but they
made an incredible amount of money
nonetheless through the sale of the
tokens and transaction fees. The
Financial Times estimates a figure of at
least $335 million.
Under the Biden administration, Trump's
and other meme coins might have been
investigated by the SEC. They're a hot
bet for wild financial speculation and
scams, and most buyers tend to lose
money, but that doesn't happen in this
case. And once Trump is in power, he
replaces the head of the SEC as
promised.
>> On day one, I will fire Gary Gensler and
appoint a new SEC chairman. Shortly
after, the agency publishes a statement
saying that memecoins are essentially
not to be investigated or regulated by
them because they can't be defined as
securities. The agency also ends their
investigation into several crypto
companies.
Experts are quick to point out a
conflict of interest. The president and
his family profit from crypto while he's
also the one setting crypto policy.
Crypto executives fear Trump's coin
could damage the industry's reputation.
one they've been working to rebuild
after years of scandals.
But it doesn't end here.
In April 2025, it's announced that the
top 220 holders of Trump's coin will be
invited to a private dinner with the
president. The top 25 will also get
access to an exclusive pre-dinner
reception and a special VIP tour of the
White House.
Mostly foreign crypto investors spent a
total of $148 million on Trump coins for
a chance to attend. Crypto entrepreneur
Justin Sun alone seems to have paid $16
million.
More on him in a minute.
The attendee list was not published, but
other notable figures included the
crypto investor Srock O kind Warwick and
the memecoin startup meme core. This
might give the impression that one can
buy access to the president of the
United States. Luckily, the White House
clarified.
>> The president is abiding by all conflict
of interest laws that are applicable.
The American public believe it's absurd
for anyone to insinuate that this
president is profiting off of the
presidency.
>> But all of this is just a tip of the
iceberg. This story has been in the news
extensively. Meanwhile, the full extent
of the Trump family's involvement in
crypto is concealed within a far more
ambitious and far less public venture.
According to Eric Trump, it's one of the
most successful things they ever did.
On September 16, 2024, Trump announced
the launch of a new venture called World
Liberty Financial. This new business is
run by his sons, Eric, Donald Jr., and
Baron. The goal is to become a kind of
crypto bank, a place where people can
borrow and lend money in digital
currencies. Their plans are laid out in
this gold paper that has Trump all over
it. He's listed as the company's chief
crypto advocate. DT Marks Defi LLC is a
corporate entity of the Trump family.
Trump's assets are managed by his
children, but he still directly benefits
from them. This entity owns roughly 40%
of World Liberty Financial. The other
four founders include Zack Witkoff and
his father Steve Witco, a real estate
mogul, longtime friend of Trump and his
special envoy to the Middle East. The
Atlantic dubbed him the Rio Secretary of
State. Then there are Zachary Faulkman,
known as Zoney and Chase Harrow. The two
were reportedly brought in through Zack
Whitov, and they had rather interesting
careers before teaming up with the
president's family to launch a crypto
bank. Z Money once ran a site called
date hotter girls.
>> Like what it is that you want to do to
this girl? Throwing her up against the
wall and ripping her clothes off.
According to the New York Times, the two
also sold colon cleanses and gave
getrich quick advice. First 14 days of
January, I made a million dollars net. I
became a man.
>> In any case, this team gets right to
work. First, World Liberty Financial
begins to sell a new cryptocurrency
called Wilfi. The Trump family is
entitled to 75% of the revenue from
these coin sales after a minimum has
been generated that will stay in the
company. Whoever buys gets voting rights
in the company in the future. The
purchase essentially makes you a
shareholder. The Trump family owns $22.5
billion of these coins. The goal is to
sell $300 million worth of this new
currency, but at the end of October,
sales are at just a few million.
Then election night changes everything.
>> Thank you very much. Wow. Incredible
movement. This was a movement like
nobody's ever seen before. I will fire
Gary Gensler and appoint a new SEC
chairman.
>> Big things on the horizon for World
Liberty Financial. Suddenly, people are
starting to buy. Many investors are from
places like Singapore, South Korea, Hong
Kong, and the United Arab Emirates. They
are legally not allowed to donate to a
presidential campaign, but Willfi offers
a nice workaround to Beck Trump. Other
investors previously had trouble with
the SEC. Here, one man stands out,
Justin Sun. At the time, the SEC is
suing him and his companies for fraud
and securities violations. They alleged
the unregistered trading of securities,
extensive wash trading to make it seem
that particular coins had trading
activity to inflate their price, and the
undisclosed promotion of two coins
through multiple celebrities.
Sun spends a total of $75 million on
World Liberty's coins after the
election. According to him, that has
nothing to do with the giant lawsuit and
is simply a vote of confidence in Trump.
Then Trump is inaugurated and Gensler
steps down as chairman of the SEC.
Shortly after, the agency requests to
pause the lawsuit against Sun.
In 2024 alone, Trump made $57 million
from Willi token sales. Word Liberty
Financial is just getting started,
though. Next step, a transformative
initiative. They supposedly set out to
help out smaller crypto companies by
investing into their coins. But the New
York Times found out that these deals
apparently have a not so public layer.
Apparently, World Liberty Financial
doesn't simply buy other coins. They may
propose asymmetrical currency swaps.
This is how it would go. A company buys
somewhere between 10 and $30 million of
Willi and in turn, World Liberty
Financial buys a smaller chunk of their
coin. This way, word liberty would
reportedly make up to a 20% premium on
these deals. The company's argument for
these types of deals is supposedly that
they're like super close to the
president. Some crypto companies
apparently felt word Liberty was
essentially selling an endorsement, but
reportedly several crypto companies
struck deals with World Liberty
Financial. Many others rejected them,
calling the supposed approach dishonest.
World Liberty Financial told the New
York Times that it would be false,
absurd, and dangerous to suggest that
investments or partnerships with World
Liberty Financial were conducted as some
sort of political quid proquo.
But the New York Times found even more
troubling coincidences.
World Liberty Financial announced a
partnership with Athena Labs in December
2024 and bought $5 million of their
cryptocurrency. One of Athena's
investors pleaded guilty to violating
the Bank Secrecy Act in 2022. Trump
pardoned him in March of 2025.
Trump also called for legislation to
govern stable coins so they could better
operate in the US. Those are
cryptocurrencies designed to always be
worth $1. Shortly after World Liberty
Financial introduced their own stable
coin, USD1. It already has a market cap
of over $2 billion, making it the fifth
biggest stable coin in the world. The
coin was used for a $2 billion
investment into Binance by MGX. Binance
is the world's largest crypto exchange.
Chungpang Zhao is the founder and former
CEO of the company. Last year, he was
sentenced to 4 months in prison after
pleading guilty to money laundering in
the US. In light of this deal, Zho met
with Zack Witkov, Zoney, and Chase
Harrow. MGX, on the other hand, is a
state-owned investment company in Abu
Dhabi. The deal was led by the National
Security Adviser of the United Arab
Emirates. Again, some worry this could
present a conflict of interest. One
could argue that through this deal, a
foreign country is directly contributing
to the financial benefit of the US
president. And this deal is just one
part of the Trump family's growing
business relations in the Middle East.
There's more, though.
The Trump Media and Technology Group is
the company behind Trump's Truth Social
platform. In May, it raised more than $2
billion to buy Bitcoin. This makes the
company effectively a giant bet on the
cryptocurrency. Just 2 months prior,
Trump had announced a national crypto
reserve. Specifically, Bitcoin and Ether
would be at the heart of it. In turn,
these two coins and many others gained
in value significantly for a period.
World Liberty Financial had also been
buying $240 million worth of Ether in
the months before the announcement. Yet
another Trump venture recently raised
$220 million for Bitcoin mining. So what
does all of this mean?
There are many moving pieces to the
story. Reports of possibly secretly sold
stakes and apparent divestment by Steve
Vitcov. New maneuvers to align Willi and
the Trump memecoin. But this is the big
picture. According to Forbes, crypto now
makes up most of Trump's wealth, around
60%. Just think about that for a second.
He inherited and expanded a real estate
empire for half a century.
Now, it took just a year for him to
double his wealth. Is it a coincidence
that this is also the year he became
president again? The year in which he
seized control of the most important
regulatory bodies around crypto. The New
York Times writes that World Liberty
Financial has erased centuries old
presidential norms, eviscerating the
boundary between private enterprise and
government policy in a manner without
precedent in modern American history.
The picture Trump's crypto ventures are
painting is that of an oligarchy where
rich people in trouble with the law
suddenly don't have trouble anymore.
Where foreign governments and investors
enrich the US leader directly and where
you get to go to the White House if you
just give the Trump family enough money.
We asked World Liberty Financial for a
comment. They did not get back to